Okay, so one way to represent this trade-off between something that's common
好了 一种表示这种在局部常用和全局罕见间的权衡
locally but rare globally is something that's called TF-IDF or
的方法称为 TF-IDF 或者
Term frequency- inverse document frequency.
词频-逆向文件频率法
Okay, so first let's describe what term frequency is, and here what we're gonna do
首先我们讨论一下什么是词频 我们要做的是
is look locally, we're looking just at the document that the person is currently
考虑局部情况 我们只看某人正在阅读的文章
reading and we simply count the number of words like we did.
简单统计单词出现的次数 就像之前做过的
So this is just our word count factor.
这个仅是单词计数
But then what we're gonna do is, we're gonna
接着我们要做的是
downweight this factor base on something called the Inverse Document Frequency.
我们将根据所谓的逆向文件频率来减小这个数的权重
So for this, we're gonna look at all documents in our corpus and
我们要做的是 考虑语料库中的所有文档
were gonna compute the following thing, which is log of
计算以下数字 也就是
the number of documents in the corpus divided by 1
语料库中的文档数除以1加上
plus the number of documents that contain the word that we're looking at.
包含我们所关心的这个单词的文档数 再取商数的对数
Okay, so let's think a little bit about why we have this form.
我们先思考为什么是这个公式
So first, let's think about a very common word.
首先 对一个非常常用的单词
So, a word appearing in many documents.
一个出现在很多文档中的单词
Well what happens?
结果会是怎样呢?
We end up with the log of some large #
我们得到一个非常大的数除以1加上
/ 1 + another large number, and
另一个非常大的数之商的对数
we'll say this is approximately log of 1,
这约等于1的对数
which is equal to 0.
等于0
So what we see here, is that we're gonna be very, very strongly downweighting all
我们所看到的是 我们将极大地减小
the way to zero, the counts of any word that appears extremely frequently.
出现频率极高的 在所有文档中都出现的
Where that appears in all of our documents.
单词的权重至0
Okay, but in contrast, if we have a rare word,
但与之相反的是 如果我们有一个生僻词
were gonna have log of, I would say, a large number,
我们将计算的是一个非常大的数 假设
assuming we have a large number of documents that
我们搜索范围包含文档数量很大
we were searching over divided by 1 + a small number,
除以1加上一个较小的数之商的对数
and this is gonna be, or to say some largish number,
结果会得到一个较大的数
or a not a zero or a small number.
或者一个非零的数或者一个较小的数
And the reason that we have this one here, is the fact that we can't assume that
之所以数字1出现在分式下方 是因为
every word appears in any document in the corpus.
我们无法假设每个单词都会出现在语料库里的某一文档中
So there might be some word in the vocabulary that doesn't appear
所以可能出现的是 词表中的某些单词
anywhere in our corpus.
不会在语料库中的任一文档出现
And so we wanna avoid dividing by 0.
因此我们想要避免除以0
Okay, so let's look at an example where there's the index for
好了 让我们看一个例子
the word the, and let's say that the appears.
这里是单词the的索引 假设the在我们考虑的文档中出现
I don't know. Something like a thousand times in
我不知道 可能1000次
the document that I'm looking at, and then there's the word messi.
单词Messi在这个位置
Messi appears five times.
Messi出现了5次
Okay, now I'm gonna look at computing the inverse document frequency for that word.
现在我要计算单词的逆向文件频率
So the word the,
先看单词the
let's assume that the word the appears in every document in the corpus.
假设单词the出现在语料库中的每个文档
Well, really every document except one, so I can do some easy math here.
或者除某一文档之外的其他文档 让计算变简单点
So, when I'm looking at this entry,
所以对这个位置的数值
I'm gonna compute log of the number of documents in the corpus and
我要计算语料库中的文档数
let's assume that we have 64 documents in this corpus.
假设这个语料库中有64个文档
And then we have 1+, and I assume that the word the didn't appear in
接着是1加上 假设单词the只在其中一个文档中不出现
one of these 64 documents, must have been a pretty short document.
那一定是一个很短的文档
And so, what this gives us is the 0 that we talking about before.
计算这个式子得到0 就像我们之前说过的
So the the gets downweighted completely by zero.
所以单词the的权重完全减小到0
In contrast, when we look at Messi, let's assume that
与此相反 当我们考虑单词Messi时
again we have some 64 total documents and
再次假设我们总共有64个文档
lets assume that the word Messi appears only in three of these documents,
假设单词Messi只出现在其中三个文档中
so we get log of 16,
所以我们得到16的对数
which if we use log base two gives us four.
如果对数以2为底就得到4
Okay, so this is our term frequency, and
所以这里是这两次单词的词频
our inverse document frequency for these two words.
以及逆向文件频率
And when we code to compute the term frequency, inverse document frequency, for
当我们计算出这个特定文档的词频和逆向文件频率
the specific document which is gonna be our new representation of this document,
来得到这个文档的新的表示时
we simply multiply these two factors together.
我们仅仅简单地将这两个向量相乘
So theres some numbers here, where the word the,
这里有些数字 在单词the的位置
turns into a 0 and then these are some other numbers and then the word
数字是0 后面还有某些数 然后
Messi is gonna be upweighted, so a weight of 20.
单词Messi的权重将会增加至20
And again,
然后以及
there's some other computation we're doing for all the other words in our vocabulary.
对词汇表中其他单词 我们可以做类似计算
But the point that we wanna make here is the fact that these very common words like
但这里我想说的是 常用词如the的权重
the, get downweighted and the rare and
减小了 而生僻词或潜在的重要单词
potentially very important words like Messi are getting upweighted.
翻译: Emilily |审阅: Coursera Global Translator Community 比如Messi 的权重增加了